Guide to the John C. Becher Soldier Show collection, 1940-1953
George Mason University Libraries
- John C. Becher Soldier Show collection
  - The Editor (Folder 38, Box 12)
    Skit by Frank J. Conboy; Item written by personnel going to school for Special Services in Lexington, Virginia 1943-1946
  - Election Scene (Folder 39, Box 12)
  - Facing the Facts (Folder 40, Box 12)
    Skit by Gene Lockhart; Item written by personnel going to school for Special Services in Lexington, Virginia 1943-1946
  - Faithful Servant (Folder 41, Box 12)
  - First Epistle to the Selected (Folder 42, Box 12)
    Skit by Pfc. Harold Fleming; Item written by personnel going to school for Special Services in Lexington, Virginia 1943-1946
  - Five Short Ones (Folder 43, Box 12)
    Various skits by Lt. W. Toll; Item written by personnel going to school for Special Services in Lexington, Virginia 1943-1946
  - 40 Below (Folder 44, Box 12)
    Skit by Pfc. M. Sternberg; Item written by personnel going to school for Special Services in Lexington, Virginia 1943-1946
  - 40 Below (Folder 45, Box 12)
  - For Meritorious Service: A Ten Minute Skit (Folder 46, Box 12)
  - Free and Equal Blues (Folder 47, Box 12)
    Song lyrics; Item written by personnel going to school for Special Services in Lexington, Virginia 1943-1946
  - Free and Equal Blues (Folder 48, Box 12)
  - Freedom of the Air (Folder 49, Box 12)
    Skit by George S. Kaufman; Item written by personnel going to school for Special Services in Lexington, Virginia 1943-1946
  - Gielgud (Folder 1, Box 13)
  - The Good Nazi: A War-Orientation Play in One Act (Folder 2, Box 13)
    Skit by Pvt. Ivan Tors; Item written by personnel going to school for Special Services in Lexington, Virginia 1943-1946
  - Goofin' Off (Folder 3, Box 13)
    Skit by 2 Lt. Frank J. Conboy; Item written by personnel going to school for Special Services in Lexington, Virginia 1943-1946
  - Granny Cracks the WACs or Vise Versa (Folder 4, Box 13)
  - Harmones (Folder 5, Box 13)
  - Have You a Little Dictator in Your Home (Folder 6, Box 13)
    Skit by Henry Blankfort and Bert Lawrence; Item written by personnel going to school for Special Services in Lexington, Virginia 1943-1946
  - Heckling Routine (Folder 7, Box 13)
  - Hollywood (Folder 8, Box 13)
  - Hospital Bit (Folder 9, Box 13)
  - Hospital Bit (Folder 10, Box 13)
  - How Green Was My Rookie (Folder 11, Box 13)
  - If Men Played Cards As Women Do (Folder 12, Box 13)
  - If Men Played Cards As Women Do (Folder 13, Box 13)
  - I Get Nothin' But respect: Song Sketch for WAC Lieutenant (Folder 14, Box 13)
  - I Have Friend Too (Folder 15, Box 13)
    Skit by Lt. Etter; Item written by personnel going to school for Special Services in Lexington, Virginia 1943-1946
  - Incident at the Gate: Blackout (Folder 16, Box 13)
    Skit by S/Sgt. Chuck Allen; Item written by personnel going to school for Special Services in Lexington, Virginia 1943-1946
  - Joining the Army (Folder 17, Box 13)
    Skit by Pfc. Charles Roth; Item written by personnel going to school for Special Services in Lexington, Virginia 1943-1946
  - Joining the Army (Folder 18, Box 13)
  - Just Sign Here (Folder 19, Box 13)
    Skit by Salem Ludwig and Joseph R. Horenstein; Item written by personnel going to school for Special Services in Lexington, Virginia 1943-1946
  - Keep 'Em Filing (Folder 20, Box 13)
    Song parody and stage directions by H. Shaffer; Item written by personnel going to school for Special Services in Lexington, Virginia 1943-1946
  - K-K-K-Katy (Folder 21, Box 13)
    Skit by S/Sgt. Robert N. Mazer and Sgt. Abe Laufe; Item written by personnel going to school for Special Services in Lexington, Virginia 1943-1946
  - K-K-K-Katy (Folder 22, Box 13)
  - Lamour Toujours Lamour (Folder 23, Box 13)
  - Latrine, Incorporated (Folder 24, Box 13)
  - Lecture (Folder 25, Box 13)
  - Lecture on Aviation (Folder 26, Box 13)
  - Lexington Lunatic Asylum (Folder 27, Box 13)
    Skit by Lt. J. R. Humphreys;Item written by personnel going to school for Special Services in Lexington, Virginia 1943-1946
  - The Lorelle (Folder 28, Box 13)
    Skit by Paul Price; Item written by personnel going to school for Special Services in Lexington, Virginia 1943-1946
  - The Love-Test (Folder 29, Box 13)
    Skit by 2 Lt. Vernon Stone; Item written by personnel going to school for Special Services in Lexington, Virginia 1943-1946
  - The Man on Top (Folder 1, Box 14)
  - Message Center (Folder 2, Box 14)
  - Message Center (Folder 3, Box 14)
  - Military Courtesy (Folder 4, Box 14)
    Skit by Lt. McLean; Item written by personnel going to school for Special Services in Lexington, Virginia 1943-1946
  - Military Drill Scene (Folder 5, Box 14)
  - Military Fantasia: Strictly G.I. (Folder 6, Box 14)
  - Military Tactics (Folder 7, Box 14)
  - Miss America (Folder 8, Box 14)
  - Mr. Guffy has the Las Word (Folder 9, Box 14)
  - A Mock Opera with Apologies to the Metropolitan (Folder 10, Box 14)
    Skit by S/Sgt. Robert N. Mazer; Item written by personnel going to school for Special Services in Lexington, Virginia 1943-1946
  - M. P. Brigade (Folder 11, Box 14)
  - My Bit (Folder 12, Box 14)
    Skit by Lt. G. [?] Carr; Item written by personnel going to school for Special Services in Lexington, Virginia 1943-1946
  - Nazi Intelligence Office (Folder 13, Box 14)
    Skit by Lt. Jack Hill; Item written by personnel going to school for Special Services in Lexington, Virginia 1943-1946
  - New Yorker Cartoon Bit (Folder 14, Box 14)
  - Nomenclature of the Handkerchief (Folder 15, Box 14)
  - Oh, My Achin' Back (Folder 16, Box 14)
  - Orientale: With No Apologies to Abbot and Costello (Folder 17, Box 14)
  - Orientation Lecture (Folder 18, Box 14)
  - Out on the Waterfront (Folder 19, Box 14)
  - Pantomime with Incidental Words September 12, 1944 (Folder 20, Box 14)
  - The Perils of Fanny -or- Tain't a Fit Nite Out fer Anybody (Folder 21, Box 14)
    Newspaper clipping; Skit by Lt. Alexander B. Reed; Item written by personnel going to school for Special Services in Lexington, Virginia 1943-1946
  - Prince Meesa Ma Shina Badust (Folder 22, Box 14)
  - Private Property (Folder 23, Box 14)
  - Problem (Folder 24, Box 14)
    Skit by Pfc. Michael Ames; Item written by personnel going to school for Special Services in Lexington, Virginia 1943-1946
  - Problem (Folder 25, Box 14)
  - Prologue (Folder 26, Box 14)
  - Revolt of Beavers (Eager) (Folder 27, Box 14)
  - R.H.I.P. (Folder 28, Box 14)
    Skit by Lt. Robert P. Crawford; Item written by personnel going to school for Special Services in Lexington, Virginia 1943-1946
  - Riddle Bit (Folder 29, Box 14)
  - The Road to Roanoke (Folder 30, Box 14)
  - 'Y' Playhouse Revue: Rudolph Rassendale (Folder 31, Box 14)
  - The Russian Spy (Folder 32, Box 14)
  - The Russian Spy (Folder 33, Box 14)
  - Questions for Truth or Consequences (Folder 34, Box 14)
  - The Sad Saga of a Sea Going Soldier (Folder 35, Box 14)
    Skit by Lt's Baskind and English; Item written by personnel going to school for Special Services in Lexington, Virginia 1943-1946
  - Selective Service (Folder 36, Box 14)
  - Send in the Bench (Folder 37, Box 14)
  - Sergeants (Folder 38, Box 14)
    Skit by W. P. Moore; Item written by personnel going to school for Special Services in Lexington, Virginia 1943-1946
  - The Sergeant's Reprimand (Folder 39, Box 14)
    Story by D. L. Champion; Item written by personnel going to school for Special Services in Lexington, Virginia 1943-1946
  - A Sex Talk with Junior (Folder 40, Box 14)
    Skit by Sam Locke; Item written by personnel going to school for Special Services in Lexington, Virginia 1943-1946
  - Sgt. Swami (Folder 41, Box 14)
    Skit by Pfc. Alfred D. Geto; Item written by personnel going to school for Special Services in Lexington, Virginia 1943-1946
  - Sgt. Swami (Folder 42, Box 14)
  - Sign Reading -- Orientation -- Ballet Music (Folder 43, Box 14)
  - A Slight Case of Murder (Folder 44, Box 14)
  - The Soldier's Deck of Cards (Folder 45, Box 14)
    Skit from Our Sunday Visitor (Catholic Editorial) Huntington, Indiana; Item written by personnel going to school for Special Services in Lexington, Virginia 1943-1946
  - Special Orders (Folder 46, Box 14)
  - Soldier Shows Ideas for Sketches (Folder 47, Box 14)
    Ideas by Cpl. Don Mann; Item written by personnel going to school for Special Services in Lexington, Virginia 1943-1946
  - Stand In (Folder 48, Box 14)
    Skit by S/Sgt. A. Hamilton; Item written by personnel going to school for Special Services in Lexington, Virginia 1943-1946
  - Stream-Lined Calisthenics (Folder 49, Box 14)
  - Stream-Lined Calisthenics (Folder 50, Box 14)
  - Strictly GI (Folder 51, Box 14)
    Skit by Arnold Auerbach; Item written by personnel going to school for Special Services in Lexington, Virginia 1943-1946
  - Supermaniacs (Folder 52, Box 14)
    by Pvt. R. Weil; Item written by personnel going to school for Special Services in Lexington, Virginia 1943-1946
  - Swing Low, Sweet Juliet (Folder 53, Box 14)
    Skit by Sgt. Abe Laufe; Item written by personnel going to school for Special Services in Lexington, Virginia 1943-1946
  - Tabloid Version of a Typical G.I. Show: So Is That (Folder 1, Box 15)
    Skit by S/Sgt. Robert M. Mazer and Sgt. Abe Laufe; Item written by personnel going to school for Special Services in Lexington, Virginia 1943-1946
  - Tank Destroyer Show (Folder 2, Box 15)
  - A Ten Minute Break: A Brief Comic Interlude About the Army (Folder 3, Box 15)
    Skit by Sgt. Fred Stewart; Item written by personnel going to school for Special Services in Lexington, Virginia 1943-1946
  - This Aint Personal Affairs (Folder 4, Box 15)
  - Three Short Blackouts (Folder 5, Box 15)
    Skits: March of Time; Eskimo Courtesy; Superstition; Item written by personnel going to school for Special Services in Lexington, Virginia 1943-1946
  - Three Songs (Folder 6, Box 15)
    Songs: Special Service Song by John Baker; I've Got Enthusiasm; Ballet and Opening; Item written by personnel going to school for Special Services in Lexington, Virginia 1943-1946
  - 'Tis Pity She's a WAC -or- The Triumph of Virtue over the Curse of T.C. 87 (Folder 7, Box 15)
    Skit by 1 Lt. Bob Wellington; Item written by personnel going to school for Special Services in Lexington, Virginia 1943-1946
  - Tooth Opera (Folder 8, Box 15)
  - A Triangular Division -or- Pardon Me! (Folder 9, Box 15)
    Skit by 2 Lt. WMA. Page; Item written by personnel going to school for Special Services in Lexington, Virginia 1943-1946
  - Try Again (Folder 10, Box 15)
  - Twenty-Three Skidoo! (Folder 11, Box 15)
  - Two of a Kind (Folder 12, Box 15)
    Skit by Sgt. Max Behm; Item written by personnel going to school for Special Services in Lexington, Virginia 1943-1946
  - Two of a Kind (Folder 13, Box 15)
  - Two Touts (Folder 14, Box 15)
    Skit by Captain Leonard Blair; Item written by personnel going to school for Special Services in Lexington, Virginia 1943-1946
  - Uniform - Class "L" (Folder 15, Box 15)
  - United Nations on the March (Folder 16, Box 15)
  - Untitled (Folder 17, Box 15)
  - Untitled (Folder 18, Box 15)
  - Untitled (Folder 19, Box 15)
  - Untitled (Folder 20, Box 15)
  - Untitled (Folder 21, Box 15)
  - The Vargas Holiday Girl (Folder 22, Box 15)
    Production suggestions by Sgt. Hez Dufenthaler; Item written by personnel going to school for Special Services in Lexington, Virginia 1943-1946
  - Vermont (Folder 23, Box 15)
  - The Voice of SPS (Folder 24, Box 15)
    Skit by Pfc. Ed Rush Rubin; Item written by personnel going to school for Special Services in Lexington, Virginia 1943-1946
  - The Women (Folder 25, Box 15)
    Skit by 2 Lt. F. J. Conboy; Item written by personnel going to school for Special Services in Lexington, Virginia 1943-1946
  - Windy's Halfway House (Folder 26, Box 15)
  - What's Your Problem (Folder 27, Box 15)
  - Welcome (Folder 28, Box 15)
  - We Are the Gals from De Boilecue (Folder 29, Box 15)
    Skit by S/Sgt. Robert Mazer; Item written by personnel going to school for Special Services in Lexington, Virginia 1943-1946
  - WACs Fifth Ave. (Folder 30, Box 15)
  - WACs Fifth Ave. (Folder 31, Box 15)
  - WACs Fifth Ave. (Folder 32, Box 15)
  - Walking in My Sleep (Folder 33, Box 15)
    Song by Lt. R. S. Beck; Item written by personnel going to school for Special Services in Lexington, Virginia 1943-1946
  - You Can't Beat Fate (Folder 34, Box 15)
  - The Pot Boiler (Folder 1, Box 16)
    Script by Alice Gerstenberg
  - Face the Facts, WAACS (Folder 2, Box 16)
  - T S Buddy! (Folder 3, Box 16)
    A Musical Revue in Five Scenes by Arthur A. Noyes, Murray L. Grand, Lionel N. Lile, and Morton J. Green
  - Soldier Theatricals - Lecture #1 (Folder 4, Box 16)
    Fundamental Purpose of Soldier Shows in Army Recreation
  - Soldier Theatricals - Lecture #1 (Folder 5, Box 16)
  - Soldier Theatricals - Lecture #2 (Folder 6, Box 16)
    The Function of the Special Service Officer as to Soldier Shows
  - Soldier Theatricals - Lecture #4 (Folder 7, Box 16)
    Informal Theatricals
  - Soldier Theatricals - Lecture #5 (Folder 8, Box 16)
    Production Planning Meetings
  - Soldier Theatricals - Lecture #6 (Folder 9, Box 16)
    Soldier Production Organization
  - Soldier Theatricals - Lecture #7 (Folder 10, Box 16)
    Soldier Stagecraft
  - Stand In (Folder 11, Box 16)
  - Tattoo (Folder 12, Box 16)
    Blackout by Lt. W. P. Moore
  - Small Games for Small People (Folder 13, Box 16)
    Blackout by Lt. Bob Eastright
  - Dasterdy Rides Again -or- Never End a Sentence with a Proposition (Folder 14, Box 16)
  - Dasterdy Rides Again -or- Never End a Sentence with a Proposition (Folder 15, Box 16)
  - Dasterdy Rides Again -or- Never End a Sentence with a Proposition (Folder 16, Box 16)
  - Blackouts (Folder 17, Box 16)
    Blackouts by Lois Landauer
  - Revue Sketches, Comedy Acts, Blackouts (Folder 18, Box 16)
    Prepared by the Entertainment Section, Special Services Branch, Royal Canadian Air Force
  - The Fifth Hi Neighbor Show on this Island (Folder 19, Box 16)
  - Burma 1943 (Folder 1, Box 17)
    Pocket Guide prepared by Special Services Division, Services of Supply, United States Army
  - Germany 1944 (Folder 2, Box 17)
    Pocket Guide prepared by Army Information Branch, Army Service Forces, United States Army
  - Great Britain May 1952 (Folder 3, Box 17)
    Pocket Guide prepared by Office of Armed Forces Information and Education, Department of Defense
  - Italian: A Guide to the Spoken Language June 1943 (Folder 4, Box 17)
    Language Guide prepared by the War Department
  - Italy September 1952 (Folder 5, Box 17)
  - Netherlands: East Indies 1944 (Folder 6, Box 17)
    Pocket Guide prepared by Special Services Division, Army Service Forces, United States Army
  - New Caledonia April 1944 (Folder 7, Box 17)
    Pocket Guide prepared by Army Information Branch, A.S.F., United States Army
  - Greece August 1953 (Folder 8, Box 17)
  - West Africa 1943 (Folder 9, Box 17)
    Pocket Guide prepared by Special Service Division, Army Service Forces, United States Army